<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dom Atkinson</title>
    <link>https://datk12.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Dom Atkinson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 11:36:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://datk12.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Linear Regression - Boston Houseprice Data</title>
      <link>https://datk12.github.io/post/linear-regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 11:36:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datk12.github.io/post/linear-regression/</guid>
      <description>Today, I will be doing a Linear Regression Analysis using the Boston House Price dataset from the Sci-Kit Learn Library. Linear Regression allows the examination of the relationship between inputs and a continuous output. In this case, the output refers to the value of the house price. We will be exploring the data to see whether or not we can learn anything about the relationships between the variables and whether we can build a model that can predict house prices based on some of the inputs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>K-Means and Satellite Imaging</title>
      <link>https://datk12.github.io/post/k-means-and-satellite-imagery/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2019 06:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datk12.github.io/post/k-means-and-satellite-imagery/</guid>
      <description>Today I will be looking at K-Means, one of the most common unsupervised machine learning algorithms for clustering problems. Clustering refers to a series of methods for finding subgroups or clusters within datasets. It is in this sense that clustering can be a thought of as an unsupervised learning method, in that we are trying to discover structure that may or may not be previously known.
The K in K-Means refers to the number of clusters we wish to partition the data into.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trump Twitter Analysis - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://datk12.github.io/post/trump-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 06:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datk12.github.io/post/trump-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Upon learning about Trump twitter archive, I immediately recognised the opportunity to subject the President’s tweets to some analysis. Without doubt President Trump, before many other politicians, understood the power of Twitter as a means of disseminating his message. His message has many characteristic features. Perhaps this is not surprising given the President&amp;rsquo;s former career as a reality television star. One phrase from the election campaign that stood out to me, an uninformed observer from outside the US, was &amp;lsquo;Crooked Hillary&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classification - Wisconsin Breast Cancer Data</title>
      <link>https://datk12.github.io/post/classification-wisconsin-breast-cancer-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 11:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datk12.github.io/post/classification-wisconsin-breast-cancer-data/</guid>
      <description>Today I will be looking at the Wisconsin Breast Cancer Data Set a pre-processed, clean data set on SKLearn. The purpose of this is to classify whether the tumour is ‘benign’ or ‘malignant’ and I will be comparing and contrasting a number of different techniques as a means of understanding the data. As this is a relatively small data set, I don&amp;rsquo;t foresee any meaningful difference in the models&amp;rsquo; power of prediciton.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://datk12.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datk12.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I’m Dom and I’m from the UK. In recent years I have become increasingly curious about new technologies and the kind of questions that can be answered by them. This is a personal blog in which I will explore some of the fields that most interest me. These include: data science, NLP, statistics amongst many others. The internet is a gold mine for data that can be used to answer real questions, if only some one asks them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>